GraphicConverter 1.8.6

Packer plugin for Total Commander to convert from one image format to another.


*** Features ***

- read many graphic formats including camera RAW;
- save to PNG, JPEG, GIF, TIFF, BMP, ICO;
- apply embedded ICC profile;
- and some more.


*** Installing ***

TC has "auto install plugin" feature. Just enter to archive with plugin and TC ask you about plugin installing. 


*** Usage ***

Select graphic files in TC, then select Files-Pack..., in combo box in Packer section panel select GraphConv.
You may change output file settings by pressing Configure button. 

Set ResetAllMetadataExtended in GraphicConverter.ini to 1 (default 0) for delete all metadata in JPEG include comment and ICC profile.
In Setup dialog option 'Reset All Metadata' must be enabled. 
Only for not "recompressed" files (if option 'Try Recompress Only if Needed' enabled).

For SVG converting plugin use rsvg-convert (from http://opensourcepack.blogspot.ru/2012/06/rsvg-convert-svg-image-conversion-tool.html).
Resize filters for SVG not used. Also percent resize not possible.

Plugin supports FreeImage 3.18.0 dll's to load webp images (FreeImage.dll, FreeImage64.dll).


*** Translations ***

Polish from dmocha.
German from TychoBarfy.
Chinese Simplified from wwj402.
Spanish from Luis Mejía.


*** License agreement ***

  This software provided "AS-IS" without warranty of any kind for non-commercial use only.


*** Changes history ***

Ver 0.9:
 * initial release.

Ver 1.2.1:
 + convert to ICO;
 * some fixes.

Ver 1.2.2:
 * Auto Adjust Orientation bug fix.

Ver 1.5 Beta:
 * graphic libraries updated;
 + basic functions for convert SVG files using RSVG converter;
 * some fixes.

Ver 1.6 Beta:
 * graphic libraries updated;
 + new parameters for enhance Camera RAW; 
 + new parameters for image sizing and JPEG save;
 * some fixes and improvements.

Ver 1.6.1 Beta:
 * graphic libraries updated;
 * improvements when convert SVG to multi icon.

Ver 1.6.2 Beta:
 * graphic libraries updated;
 + change image size in percent;
 + thumbnail size for JPEG (ThumbnailSize in GraphicConverter.ini, default 256);
 * some fixes and improvements.

Ver 1.6.2.1 Beta:
 * some fixes and improvements.

Ver 1.6.2.2 Beta:
 * converter RSVG-Convert updated to version 2.40.20;
 + HighPriority=1 in GraphicConverter.ini [Setup] section: set high priority for converter;
 * keep alpha channel when save to BMP;
 * some fixes and improvements.

Ver 1.7 Beta:
 * graphic libraries updated;
  * improved RAW support with LibRaw library, must be enabled in Setup first;
 * changes and bug fixes.

Ver 1.7.1 Beta:
 + Language= in GraphicConverter.ini [Setup] section: interface language (example: Language=English.lng).

Ver 1.7.1.1 Beta:
 + JPEG file size (very slow), must be enabled in Setup first.

Ver 1.7.1.2:
 + JPEGMaxFileSizeQualityWriteToComment=0 in GraphicConverter.ini [Setup] section: write quality to JPEG comment when max file size option enabled;
 * some fixes.

Ver 1.7.1.3:
 * some fixes.

Ver 1.7.1.4 Beta:
 * some fixes.

Ver 1.7.1.5 Beta:
 * graphic libraries updated;
 * Floyd-Steinberg dithering for GIF and 256 colors PNG.

Ver 1.7.2 Beta:
 * graphic libraries updated;
 * some fixes.

Ver 1.7.2.1 Beta:
 + Polish translation;
 * read ICO and convert SVG to ICO fixes.

Ver 1.7.3 Beta:
 + SVGReadXMLFirst=1 in GraphicConverter.ini [Setup] section: before convert SVG read it size from file first;
 + send conversion to background (but plugin not support multithread: only one conversion still possible); 
 * some fixes.

Ver 1.8 Beta:
 * graphic libraries updated;
  * updated LibRaw library with CR3 format support;
 + PNG compression for large icons.

Ver 1.8.0.1 Beta:
 * updated Polish translation;
 * convert SVG to ICO fixes.

Ver 1.8.0.2 Beta:
 + German translation;
 * some fixes.

Ver 1.8.2 Beta:
 * some fixes.

Ver 1.8.3 Beta:
 * graphic libraries updated;
 * some fixes.

Ver 1.8.4 Beta:
 * graphic libraries updated;
 + new options;
 * some fixes.

Ver 1.8.4.1 Beta:
 * Polish translation updated;
 * fixes.

Ver 1.8.4.2 Beta:
 + ThumbnailAllowCalculateQuality=0 in GraphicConverter.ini [Setup] section: decrease thumbnail quality when EXIF larger than 65K;
 * fixes.

Ver 1.8.6:
 * fixes.


---
Suggestions, Wishes and bug reports are welcome!
ProgMan13, (ProgMan13@mail.ru)